Kateryna Chonka

Technical Writer

CONTACT

(347) 613-1072 Philadelphia, PA katchonka@gmail.com kchonka.github.io

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree:
Computer Science
CUNY Hunter College
New York, NY, June 2020

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Technical Writer

Technical Writer HQ Remote, July 2024

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- AWS
- Bitbucket
- Confluence
- Docker
- Git
- GitHub
- Google Suite
- Jenkins
- JIRA
- LucidChart
- Markdown
- MySQL
- OpenAPI
- Redoc
- Swagger
- Terraform

SUMMARY

Former software engineer with 3+ years of backend development experience transitioning to technical writing after obtaining a Technical Writer certification. Demonstrated ability in creating documentation for intricate systems, including over 20 software tutorials and developer guides that enhanced team comprehension, productivity, and understanding.

WORK HISTORY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Amplify | New York, NY (Remote) | August 2022 - October 2023

- Advanced the development of 6 microservice applications on an agile, back-end team.
- Designed and engineered four REST API endpoints using the Serverless and FastAPI frameworks with Python to build an internal troubleshooting tool.
- Implemented documentation-as-code practices to expand API documentation in Swagger, facilitating easier access and understanding for cross-functional teams.
- Enhanced team collaboration and knowledge sharing by creating software tutorials and documentation for new features, expanding the team's Google Drive repository.
- Authored process documentation for the 1EdTech certification process for compliance with the Learning Tools Interoperability (LTI) standard.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CureMetrix | La Jolla, CA (Remote) | February 2021 - August 2022

- Collaborated with research, product, and regulatory teams on developing four medical
 CAD AI software products for mammography analysis using a waterfall methodology.
- Generated detailed Lucidchart diagrams outlining software architecture and workflows to support three ongoing FDA submissions.
- Optimized 10+ Python scripts from the research team for production, improving overall software quality, speed, and maintenance.
- Transformed Python code for DICOM medical image processing by consolidating over 30 raw scripts into four packages, enhancing cross-team usability and software maintenance.
- Coauthored Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) for software processes with the quality team, resulting in increased compliance and enhanced audit readiness.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Kazuhm | San Diego, CA (Remote) | November 2021 - February 2022

- Engaged in **code reviews** and **daily scrum meetings** to enhance collaboration and maintain high code quality within a small agile team.
- Coordinated with senior developers to containerize Python applications with Docker and integrate into distributed workflows, facilitating student density monitoring on a college campus from four Raspberry Pi devices during the COVID-19 pandemic.